Guide to the Witness to Guantanamo Video Collection, 2009-2017 RL.11691
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Interviews, 2009-2017; 10,000 Gigabytes secure server
  - Shimkus, Albert, 2011-08-09; 1:52:30
    - Shimkus, Albert - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file AlbertShimkus.mov)
    - Shimkus, Albert - short clip - BSCT-Behavioral Science Control Team (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AlbertShimkus_BSCT-Behavioral Science Control Team.mp4)
    - Shimkus, Albert - short clip - HungerStrikesintheEarlyDays (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AlbertShimkus_HungerStrikesintheEarlyDays.mp4)
    - Shimkus, Albert - short clip - Looking Back (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AlbertShimkus_Looking Back.mp4)
  - Skaggs, Marshal, 2015-10-23; 2:01:57
    Marshal Skaggs, male, age 35, joined the military at age 20, and although trained in counterintelligence, he was assigned to be an interrogator after 9/11.
    - Skaggs, Marshal - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file MarshalSkaggs.mov)
    - Skaggs, Marshal - short clip - FearUpHarshIsReallyEffective (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MarshallSkaggs_FearUpHarshIsReallyEffective.mp4)
    - Skaggs, Marshal - short clip - How to Keep This From Happening Again (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MarshallSkaggs_How to Keep This From Happening Again.mp4)
    - Skaggs, Marshal - short clip - The More You Understand a Person, the More of a Person They Are to You (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MarshallSkaggs_The More You Understand a Person, the More of a Person They Are to You.mp4)
  - Sloan, Cliff, 2015-02-11; 0:50:11
    Cliff Sloan, male, age 57, was the Special Envoy for Guantanamo Closure for the Obama administration from July 2013 to December 2104, transferring 44 men out of Guantanamo.
    - Sloan, Cliff - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file CliffSloan.mov)
    - Sloan, Cliff - short clip - SingleGreatestWaytoCombatTerrorism (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file CliffSloan_SingleGreatestWaytoCombatTerrorism.mp4)
    - Sloan, Cliff - short clip - TheOnesWithTheWorstLuck (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file CliffSloan_TheOnesWithTheWorstLuck.mp4)
  - Smith, Clive Stafford, 2010-08-03; 2:02:16
    Clive Stafford Smith, male, age 51, is the founder of Reprieve and has spent 25 years working on civil rights issues, including achieving due process for prisoners detained in Guantanamo.
    - Smith, Clive Stafford - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file CliveStaffordSmith.mov)
    - Smith, Clive Stafford - short clip - CensoredbyAmericans (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file CliveStaffordSmith_CensoredbyAmericans.mp4)
    - Smith, Clive Stafford - short clip - HowtoKeepAmericaSafe (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file CliveStaffordSmith_HowtoKeepAmericaSafe.mp4)
    - Smith, Clive Stafford - short clip - SecretListofPrisoners (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file CliveStaffordSmith_SecretListofPrisoners.mp4)
  - Soufan, Ali, 2014-10-27; 1:37:45
    Ali Soufan, male, age 43, one of a few FBI agents who spoke Arabic in 2001, publicly criticized the CIA for not sharing information with him that might have led to uncovering and preventing the 9/11 attacks.
    - Soufan, Ali - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file AliSoufan.mov)
    - Soufan, Ali - short clip - ComingCleanAboutTorture (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AliSoufan_ComingCleanAboutTorture.mp4)
    - Soufan, Ali - short clip - ComingCleanAboutTorture-review (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AliSoufan_ComingCleanAboutTorture-review.mp4)
    - Soufan, Ali - short clip - WeNeedaStrategyAgainstTerrorism (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AliSoufan_WeNeedaStrategyAgainstTerrorism.mp4)
    - Soufan, Ali - short clip - WeNeedaStrategyAgainstTerrorism-review (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AliSoufan_WeNeedaStrategyAgainstTerrorism-review.mp4)
  - Souza, Alfred, 2012-04-14; 1:30:35
    Alfred Souza, male, age 41, was a biomedical equipment repair technician in the Guantanamo Bay detention center medical clinic from July to December of 2004.
    - Souza, Alfred - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file AlfredSouza.mov)
    - Souza, Alfred - short clip - HeldtotheHigherStandard (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AlfredSouza_HeldtotheHigherStandard.mp4)
    - Souza, Alfred - short clip - Timmy (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AlfredSouza_Timmy.mp4)
  - Supervielle, Manuel, 2012-09-08; 2:44:51
    Manuel Supervielle, male, age 55, was the chief military lawyer at Southern Command, and the senior military lawyer for detention operations at Guantanamo Bay. In the spirit of transparency, as the first planeload of detainees was about to arrive in Guantanamo, he invited the International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC) to visit the base.
    - Supervielle, Manuel - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file ManuelSupervielle.mov)
    - Supervielle, Manuel - short clip - DirectlyInvitingtheRedCrosstoGuantanamo (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file ManuelSupervielle_DirectlyInvitingtheRedCrosstoGuantanamo.mp4)
    - Supervielle, Manuel - short clip - SwearingAllegiancetotheConstitution (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file ManuelSupervielle_SwearingAllegiancetotheConstitution.mp4)
  - Svendsen, Kent, 2010-10-30; 1:29:31
    Kent Svendsen, male, age 58, served as chaplain for the military police battalion in Guantanamo from May 2004 to March 2005, working inside Camp Delta for the commanding officer and the troops.
    - Svendsen, Kent - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file KentSvendsen.mov)
    - Svendsen, Kent - short clip - ForbiddentoSpeaktoDetainees (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file KentSvendsen_ForbiddentoSpeaktoDetainees.mp4)
    - Svendsen, Kent - short clip - HowGuantanamoChangedMe (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file KentSvendsen_HowGuantanamoChangedMe.mp4)
    - Svendsen, Kent - short clip - IndoctrinatingNewSoldiers (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file KentSvendsen_IndoctrinatingNewSoldiers.mp4)
  - Taft, William Howard, IV, 2012-11-13; 1:12:38
    William Howard Taft IV, male, age 67, was Legal Advisor to Secretary of State Colin Powell (2001-2004), and drafted a memo on January 2, 2002 arguing the U.S. should apply the Geneva Conventions to detainees captured in the War on Terror.
    - Taft, William Howard, IV - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file WilliamHowardTaftIV.mov)
    - Taft, William Howard, IV - short clip - DeptofDefenseOkaysSuspendingGenevaConvention (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file WilliamTaft_DeptofDefenseOkaysSuspendingGenevaConvention.mp4)
    - Taft, William Howard, IV - short clip - TortureMemosSurprisedStateDept (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file WilliamTaft_TortureMemosSurprisedStateDept.mp4)
  - Taylor, Katherine, 2015-07-16; 1:03:23
    Katherine Taylor, female, age 37, is the coordinator of Reprieve's Life after Guantanamo Project, where she facilitates the transfer and resettlement of former Guantanamo detainees to countries across Europe.
    - Taylor, Katherine - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file KatherineTaylor.mov)
    - Taylor, Katherine - short clip - Post-GuantanamoStruggles (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file KatherineTaylor_Post-GuantanamoStruggles.mp4)
    - Taylor, Katherine - short clip - Post-GuantanamoStruggles-final (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file KatherineTaylor_Post-GuantanamoStruggles-final.mp4)
    - Taylor, Katherine - short clip - TheCruelestPart (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file KatherineTaylor_TheCruelestPart.mp4)
    - Taylor, Katherine - short clip - TheCruelestPart-final (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file KatherineTaylor_TheCruelestPart-final.mp4)
    - Taylor, Katherine - short clip - WorkMyselfOutofaJob (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file KatherineTaylor_WorkMyselfOutofaJob.mp4)
  - Tourson, Ahmed, 2010-01-03; 1:59:33
    Ahmed Tourson, male, age 38, a Uyghur from the Xinjiang autonomous region, was detained in Guantanamo from January 21, 2002 until October 31, 2009, when he was released to Palau.
    - Tourson, Ahmed - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file AhmedTourson.mov)
  - Urbina, Ricardo, 2015-02-10; 1:27:55
    Ricardo Urbina, male, age 69, was a US District Court Judge in the District of Columbia from 1994 to 2012, serving as Senior Judge from 2011-12. He presided over several Guantanamo habeas corpus cases, including one for seventeen Uyghur prisoners, ordering their release to the U.S. if no other country would take them. His decision was overturned by the Court of Appeals.
    - Urbina, Ricardo - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file RicardoUrbina.mov)
    - Urbina, Ricardo - short clip - FindingOrderOutofChaos (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file RicardoUrbina_FindingOrderOutofChaos.mp4)
    - Urbina, Ricardo - short clip - StuckWithoutAPlacetoGo (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file RicardoUrbina_StuckWithoutAPlacetoGo.mp4)
  - Vandeveld, Darrel, 2010-09-04; 2:56:24
    Darrel Vandeveld, male, age 49, was a prosecutor for the Office of Military Commissions at Guantanamo from June 2007 through September 2008. While acting as the lead prosecutor in the case against Mohammed Jawad, he resigned for ethical reasons and appeared as a witness for the defense.
    - Vandeveld, Darrel - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file DarrelVandeveld.mov)
    - Vandeveld, Darrel - short clip - ParticipatinginEvil (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file DarrelVandeveld_ParticipatinginEvil.mp4)
    - Vandeveld, Darrel - short clip - ReexaminingBasicBeliefs (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file DarrelVandeveld_ReexaminingBasicBeliefs.mp4)
    - Vandeveld, Darrel - short clip - ReexaminingBasicBeliefs (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file DarrelVandeveld_ReexaminingBasicBeliefs.mp4)
    - Vandeveld, Darrel - short clip - TheAlgerianSix (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file DarrelVandeveld_TheAlgerianSix.mp4)
  - Vokey, Colby, 2012-09-29; 1:52:59
    Colby Vokey, male, age 47, served as lead counsel to former Guantanamo detainee Omar Khadr, a Canadian who was captured at 15 and was still a juvenile when he was brought to Guantanamo.
    - Vokey, Colby - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file ColbyVokey.mov)
    - Vokey, Colby - short clip - InventingaLegalSystem (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file ColbyVokey_InventingaLegalSystem.mp4)
    - Vokey, Colby - short clip - PunishedforHavingaLawyer (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file ColbyVokey_PunishedforHavingaLawyer.mp4)
    - Vokey, Colby - short clip - SystemDesignedtoConvict (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file ColbyVokey_SystemDesignedtoConvict.mp4)
  - Walker, Marilyn, 2013-01-05; 2:01:57
    Marilyn Walker, female, age 62, is the mother of John Walker Lindh, a 20 year-old American citizen captured in Afghanistan in November 2001 in connection with his participation in the Taliban, and held for 54 days without access to his family and lawyers.
    - Walker, Marilyn - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file MarilynWalker.mov)
    - Walker, Marilyn - short clip - AcceptingThePleaBargain (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MarilynWalker_AcceptingThePleaBargain.mp4)
    - Walker, Marilyn - short clip - HardToSeeHimGo (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MarilynWalker_HardToSeeHimGo.mp4)
    - Walker, Marilyn - short clip - JohnsLifeAfterPrison (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MarilynWalker_JohnsLifeAfterPrison.mp4)
  - Walls, Glendale, 2015-07-27; 1:14:53
    Glendale Walls, male, age 33, was a military intelligence interrogator at Bagram Air Force Base, Afghanistan. He was accused of using abusive interrogation techniques and charged with assaulting and mistreating a detainee, Dilawar of Yakubi, an Afghan taxi driver, who later died at the prison.
    - Walls, Glendale - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file GlendaleWalls.mov)
    - Walls, Glendale - short clip - Self-PolicingInterrogators (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file GlendaleWalls_Self-PolicingInterrogators.mp4)
  - Wilkerson, Lawrence, 2011-03-19; 1:46:21
    Lawrence Wilkerson, male, age 66, is former chief of staff to U.S. Secretary of State, Colin Powell, and former director of the U.S.-Cuba Policy Initiative with the American Strategy Program at the New America Foundation.
    - Wilkerson, Lawrence - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file LawrenceWilkerson.mov)
    - Wilkerson, Lawrence - short clip - CheneysCowardice (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file ColLawrenceWilkerson_CheneysCowardice.mp4)
    - Wilkerson, Lawrence - short clip - PoliticsofFear (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file ColLawrenceWilkerson_PoliticsofFear.mp4)
    - Wilkerson, Lawrence - short clip - PresidentBeholdenToOutsideInterests (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file ColLawrenceWilkerson_PresidentBeholdenToOutsideInterests.mp4)
  - Williamson, Clint, 2013-07-29; 1:47:18
    Clint Williamson, male, age 51, was the Ambassador-at-Large for War Crimes Issues from 2006 to 2009, during which he led international resettlement for Guantanamo detainees.
    - Williamson, Clint - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file ClintWilliamson.mov)
    - Williamson, Clint - short clip - ADivideBetweenStateandDefense (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file ClintWilliamson_ADivideBetweenStateandDefense.mp4)
    - Williamson, Clint - short clip - PresidentPopularityandRepatriatingDetainees (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file ClintWilliamson_PresidentPopularityandRepatriatingDetainees.mp4)
    - Williamson, Clint - short clip - YouCantLockThemAllUp (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file ClintWilliamson_YouCantLockThemAllUp.mp4)
  - Wilner, Tom, 2010-08-09; 2:09:51
    Tom Wilner, male, age 66, represented several Kuwaiti detainees before the Supreme Court after being contacted by their families in early 2002. He was Counsel of record to Guantanamo detainees in Rasul v. Bush, decided in June 2004, and counsel of record in Boumediene v. Bush, decided in June 2008.
    - Wilner, Tom - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file TomWilner.mov)
    - Wilner, Tom - short clip - GuantanamoTooPoliticalForMediaCoverage (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file TomWilner_GuantanamoTooPoliticalForMediaCoverage.mp4)
    - Wilner, Tom - short clip - GuantanamoTooPoliticalForMediaCoverage (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file TomWilner_GuantanamoTooPoliticalForMediaCoverage.mp4)
    - Wilner, Tom - short clip - GuantanamoTooPoliticalForMediaCoverage2 (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file TomWilner_GuantanamoTooPoliticalForMediaCoverage2.mp4)
    - Wilner, Tom - short clip - SeeingFamilyFortheFirstTimeinThreeYears (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file TomWilner_SeeingFamilyFortheFirstTimeinThreeYears.mp4)
    - Wilner, Tom - short clip - SeeingFamilyFortheFirstTimeinThreeYears (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file TomWilner_SeeingFamilyFortheFirstTimeinThreeYears.mp4)
    - Wilner, Tom - short clip - WhatHappenedWithObama (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file TomWilner_WhatHappenedWithObama.mp4)
  - Wolosky, Lee, 2017-03-10; 0:44:37
    Lee Wolosky, male, age 48 was appointed Special Envoy for Guantanamo Closure at the U.S. State Department under President Obama from July 5, 2015 until January 20, 2017. During his tenure, the number of men remaining at Guantanamo went from roughly 116 down to 41.
    - Wolosky, Lee - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file LeeWolosky.mov)
    - Wolosky, Lee - short clip - BiPartisanSupportforClosingGtmo (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file LeeWolosky_BiPartisanSupportforClosingGtmo.mp4)
    - Wolosky, Lee - short clip - ConvincingCountriestoTakeDetainees (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file LeeWolosky_ConvincingCountriestoTakeDetainees.mp4)
  - Worthington, Andy, 2016-12-11; 1:26:22
    Andy Worthington, male, age 53, a British historian and investigative journalist, is the author of "The Guantanamo Files: The Stories of 759 Detainees in America's Illegal Prison," "The Complete Guantanamo Files," and co-director of the documentary "Outside the Law: Stories of Guantanamo."
    - Worthington, Andy - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file AndyWorthington.mov)
    - Worthington, Andy - short clip - SeeingGuantanamoasanOpportunityforGrowth (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AndyWorthington_SeeingGuantanamoasanOpportunityforGrowth.mp4)
    - Worthington, Andy - short clip - TheFundamentalRacismofGuantanamo (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AndyWorthington_TheFundamentalRacismofGuantanamo.mp4)
    - Worthington, Andy - short clip - UncoveringtheTruth (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AndyWorthington_UncoveringtheTruth.mp4)
  - Xenakis, Stephen, 2011-08-11; 1:38:28
    Stephen Xenakis, male, age 63, was an Army Brigadier General, and advised senior Department of Defense officials on issues of psychological health. As an expert on torture, he provided legal testimony on behalf of current and former detainees.
    - Xenakis, Stephen - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file StephenXenakis.mov)
    - Xenakis, Stephen - short clip - 1 (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file StephenXenakis_1.mp4)
    - Xenakis, Stephen - short clip - GitmoGoo (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file StephenXenakis_GitmoGoo.mp4)
    - Xenakis, Stephen - short clip - WhyPeopleGoOnHungerStrike (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file StephenXenakis_WhyPeopleGoOnHungerStrike.mp4)
  - Yadel, Brahim, 2009-08-15; 2:26:27
    Brahim Yadel, male, age 38, French, was detained in Guantanamo from January 2002 until July 26, 2004, when he was released to France.
    - Yadel, Brahim - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file BrahimYadel.mov)
    - Yadel, Brahim - short clip - FirstInterrogation (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file BrahimYadel_FirstInterrogation.mp4)
    - Yadel, Brahim - short clip - GoWiththeFlow (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file BrahimYadel_GoWiththeFlow.mp4)
    - Yadel, Brahim - short clip - InterrogationDuringSurgery (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file BrahimYadel_InterrogationDuringSurgery.mp4)
    - Yadel, Brahim - short clip - InterrogationDuringSurgery (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file BrahimYadel_InterrogationDuringSurgery.mp4)
    - Yadel, Brahim - short clip - InterrogatorsOversawEverything (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file BrahimYadel_InterrogatorsOversawEverything.mp4)
    - Yadel, Brahim - short clip - MakinganExample (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file BrahimYadel_MakinganExample.mp4)
  - Yee, James, 2010-12-05; 2:24:53
    James Yee, male, age 42, served as the Muslim Chaplain in Guantanamo from November 2002 until September 2003. After being officially recognized for outstanding performance, he was arrested and imprisoned in a Naval brig for 76 days while on leave in Florida. No evidence was released, and eventually all charges were dropped.
    - Yee, James - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file JamesYee.mov)
  - Zemmouri, Mosa, 2013-07-30; 1:16:52
    Mosa Zemmouri, male, age 35, a Belgian citizen of Moroccan heritage, was detained in Guantanamo from February 15, 2002 until April 25, 2005, when he was returned to Belgium.
    - Zemmouri, Mosa - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file MosaZemmouri.mov)
    - Zemmouri, Mosa - short clip - HungerStrike (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MosaZemmouri_HungerStrike.mp4)
    - Zemmouri, Mosa - short clip - IsolationBeforeGoingHome (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MosaZemmouri_IsolationBeforeGoingHome.mp4)
    - Zemmouri, Mosa - short clip - IsolationBeforeGoingHome-old (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MosaZemmouri_IsolationBeforeGoingHome-old.mp4)
    - Zemmouri, Mosa - short clip - WorshipersofAmerica (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MosaZemmouri_WorshipersofAmerica.mp4)